Los Cuates De Sinaloa[墨西哥乐队名]
《黑与蓝》
在那新墨西哥州  有个小城叫做杜克
在当地黑帮  有个鬼佬正声名鹊起
都是因为他所制的毒品
据说这货颜色纯蓝  品质纯正
强力冰毒已在街头泛滥
即使想阻止  已是有心无力
贩毒集团怒火中烧  因为权威受到挑战
传说如今的市场  是个叫"海森堡"的天下
只是没人能一睹真容  所以没人认识他
贩毒集团绝不会善罢甘休
这家伙死期将至  却还被蒙在鼓里
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：小鱼      校对：小路     时间轴：虫不知
特效：Will      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
海森堡的威名  早已远播墨西哥[米却肯:墨西哥一州名]
无论远近  这个货都供不应求
这蓝色东东已经跨越了国境
如今的新墨西哥州终于名副其实
因为毒品泛滥  它成了墨西哥第二
只是鬼佬已成毒枭  他被称作"海森堡"
贩毒集团怒火中烧  因为权威受到挑战
传说如今的市场  是个叫"海森堡"的天下
只是没人能一睹真容  所以没人认识他
贩毒集团的怒火  至今还无人能幸免
这家伙死期将至  却还被蒙在鼓里
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第七集
氮和氧通过化学键结合
Nitrogen bonds to oxygen,
就会转化为
Which, in turn...
你知道什么是化学键吧
You do know what a bond is?
一种强烈的吸引力
A strong force of attraction.
比如共价键  离子键
Covalent bonds, ionic bonds.
原子和分子相互结合组成化合物
The coming together of atoms and molecules to form compounds?
正是化学键
Chemical bonds
让物质成为了物质
Are what make matter matter.
正是化学键  把物质世界联系起来
Bonds are what hold the physical world together,
把我们联系起来
What hold us together.
是, 我知道
yeah, I know
我知道了
I got it.
化学键
Bonds.
你的考试成绩可不这么说
Your test score says otherwise.
正说明你啥都没搞懂
It tells me you don't get it at all.
58分  差不多了
I mean, 58. I was close.
什么叫差不多了
What is close?
科学领域可没有"差不多"一说  巴里
There's no "close" in science, Barry.
只有正确错误之分
There are right answers and wrong answers.
"差不多"可不能让人类登上月球
"Close" didn't put men on the moon.
是, 但是
Yeah, but...
我只是想说  才两分而已  怀特先生
I'm just saying, Mr. White, 2 points?
如果我化学不过  就得参加暑假补习班
If I don't pass chemistry,I have to go to summer school.
我是说  我真的用功了
I mean, I really studied. Like,really
真的  真的用功了
Really, really studied, like,
甚至是废寝忘食的
all night hard.I mean...
我对化学很感兴趣的
I'm so into chemistry for, like,
比如这些概念什么的  我只是觉得
The concepts.I just think I might have
我可能得了注意力缺陷症
The attention deficit.
你就不能放我一马吗
Couldn't you please just let this slide?
别痴人说梦了
Don't bullshit a bullshitter.
不行  下次自己发愤图强吧
The answer is no.Next time, apply yourself.
认识我的  就留个口信吧
Yo, if I know you, leave a message.
你是在躲着我还是怎么着
Are you ducking me or what?
我都打了三个电话给你了
This makes the third time.
听着  我这手机
Look, I will be
会继续开机15分钟  给我回电
Leaving this phone on for another 15 minutes, so call me.
还有
And by the way,
上次我们说的那事
That thing we talked about?
我跟你说"处理掉"
When I said "handle it"?
不用麻烦了
Well, don't.
就这么吧
Let it go.
挂了
All right.
杰西  给我开门
Jessi.Open the door.
我知道你在家  看到你的车了  快开门
I know you're home.Your car is here. Come on.
要我帮忙吗
Can I help you?
不用了  谢谢
No,thank you.
我是房东
I'm the manager,
别再敲了  好吗
So can we stop with the pounding, please?
你是房东
You're the manager?
对   对
Yes yes
那你绝对能帮得上我
You can help me.Absolutely.
我得进屋去
I very much need to get inside here.
你有备用钥匙的话  你有钥匙的吧
So if you have a master key...You have a key, right?
对  我有
Yeah, I have a key.
听着  住这里的这个人
Look, the person who lives here,
我得马上见他  这非常重要
It's just very important for me to see him.
你敲过门了  对吗
And you knocked, right?
他没来应门
He didn't answer?
知道什么意思吧
Which means?
听着  我是他父亲  好吧
Look, I'm his father, all right?
你是杰克逊先生
You're Mr. Jackson?
就是我  沃尔特·杰克逊
Yes ,that's me. Walt Jackson.
-请问你是  -珍妮
- And you are? - Jane.
很高兴见到你  珍妮  如果你不介意
Jane .Very nice to meet you, Jane.Now, if you wouldn't mind...
杰克逊先生  我很乐意借你电话一用
Mr. Jackson, I'm happy to let you use my phone.
想给他打个电话吗
Want to call him?
不想
No.
不想  我
No.I...
我说过了  我想麻烦你让我进屋
As I said, I would like to have you let me inside here
这样我可以看看我儿子的情况
So that I can check on my son's well-being.
明白吗
You understand?
你和你儿子之间的事  是你们的家务事
Look, whatever's going on between the two of you is family.
我可不想卷进去
I don't get involved in family.
杰西不想让你进去的话  你就不能进去
Jesse doesn't want you in,you're not getting in.
大姨妈来了  态度不好  抱歉
Period. Sorry.
进来吧
Come on in...
谢了
Thanks.
你还好吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
杰西·杰克逊
Jesse Jackson?
你到底
Do you even...
至少你还有个电话
I see you have a telephone at least.
知道我一直打给你是什么事吧
You know, that blinking thing I've been calling you on?
随便吧  老兄
Whatever, man.
-还给我  -再抢我就摔了它  我就摔了它
- Give me my...- I will break this! I will break this!
TM就会吸毒的笨蛋
Damn druggy idiot.
我找了你那么久
Is this what you've been doing the whole time
你就一直这么窝着吸这个吗
I've been trying to reach you?
当然不是
No.
我出去处理事情了
I've been taking care of business.
-什么事情  -你问我什么事情
- What business? - What business?
你逼着我做的事情  混蛋
The business you put me on, asshole.
你忘了吗
You already forgot?
就是这个事情
This business.
这个有没有让你想起点什么
Does that jog your memory?
你个王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
-你不会真的  -你说了  "处理掉"
- You didn't actually... - You said "handle it."
所以我把他解决了
So I handled it.
我说"处理掉"的意思  是让你恐吓威胁他
When I said "handle it,"I meant fear and intimidation.
是让你把钱拿回来
Get your money back.
-我从来没有让你  -没有让我去杀人的意思吗
- I certainly never meant for you...- You didn't mean to kill somebody?
没有
No
太晚了  因为那家伙已经挂了
Too late, yo, because dude's dead.
我的天
Oh, God.
-懂了吗  死翘翘了  -天
- All right? Way dead. - Oh, God.
给你  这是你的钱
Here.Here's your money.
4660块
4,660 bucks.
你的那一半
Your half.
留着小命好好花吧  你这个该死的混蛋
Spend it in good health,you miserable son of a bitch.
我可没说是我杀了他
I didn't say I killed him.
告诉我怎么回事
Tell me what happened.
那家伙的老婆用台自动取款机
The dude's wife crushed his head
砸烂了他的脑袋
with an ATM machine.
-砸烂了他的  -用台自动取款机砸烂了他的脑袋
- Crushed his...- Crushed his head with an ATM machine.
就在我的面前
Right in front of me.
我是说  就像在砸
I mean, crushed it like...
我的老天  那个声音
Oh, my God, the sound...
那声音怎么都忘不了
It's still in my ears.
还有那血  喷得到处都是
You know, and the blood,like, everywhere.
怎么会有那么多血  简直无法置信
Like, there was so much,you would not believe.
老兄  你就行行好给我吧
Man, will you just please give me...
把大麻还我  好吗
Just ..Give my weed, all right?
至少能让我不再反胃
It helps with my nausea.
这么说
So
你没有杀人
you did not kill anyone.
会有人以为你杀人了吗
Does anybody think that you killed anybody?
是我报的警
I called the cops.
你报的警
You called the cops?
我报警之后就溜了
I called and I split,
然后他们就过来抓了她
And then they came in and busted her.
天  她简直就是疯掉了
God, she was so zapped out of her mind.
无缘无故就这么杀了他
She did it for, like, nothing.
他是骂她贱货了  但她本来就是贱货啊
He told her she was a skank, but,I mean, she was a skank.
这人能认出你来吗
And this  person identify you?
她能指认你当时就在那吗
Can she identify you being there?
老兄  她连自己是谁都不知道了
Dude, she couldn't identify her left ass cheek.
毒瘾发作已经神志不清了
She was so zonked.
还有  她还有个
And she had this...
老天  她居然还有个孩子
God, she had this kid.
我还是搞不清楚这些细节
Listen, I'm a little fuzzy on the mechanics, here.
难道
But
你就不能阻止那女人杀掉他吗
could you not stop this woman from killing this man?
她拿枪指着我  好吗
Look, she had a gun on me, all right?
对  就是用我的枪  我的
Yeah, my gun, okay? Mine.
继续问啊  说啊
Go ahead.Say it.
我不是屠库也不是疯狂小八  我服不了众
I ain't no Tuco or Krazy-8.I can't run a crew.
说出来吧  说重点  老兄
Come on.Point made, man. Point made.yes
认识我的  就留个口信吧
Yo, if I know you, leave a message.
老兄  我是猴子
It's Badger, man.
你在干什么  别用真名
What are you doing? Don't use your real name.
什么  这不是真名啊
What? That isn't my real name.
你要的裤子到货了
We got those pants you wanted.
32号的尺寸  对吗
32 large, right?
我们已经给你准备好了  老板
We got them just for you,Jefe.
一手交钱一手交货吧
Let's do some bid-ness, yo.
那么  你还会回去做老本行吗
So, are you going to get back up on that horse?
你去吧
You get on.
好吗
All right?
我只想忘掉这一切
I just want to forget.
抱歉
Sorry.
那个要来干嘛的
What's up with that?
马尔贝尔德
Jesus Malverde
墨西哥毒贩的守护神
Patron saint of Mexican drug dealers.
见鬼  我知道他是谁  好吧
Hell, I know who it is, okay?
那帮混蛋就会给他下跪  还念念有词地祈祷呢
Scumbags kneeling down,praying to him...
"求求你  伟大的守护神"
"Please, Senior Saint-ay!"
"保佑我别让禁毒署逮住"
"No DEA, please!"
我只是问问为啥要把他放你桌上
I'm just saying why is he on your desk?
想抓新纳粹  也不必戴着万字符  对吧
Going after neo-Nazis,you don't wear swastikas, right?
孙子
Sun Tzu.
公元前6世纪的中国军师  著有《孙子兵法》一书
Sixth century Chinese general.Wrote The Art Of War.
"知己知彼"
"If you know your enemies yourself,"
"百战不殆"
"you'll fight without danger in many battles."
有才
Right on.
-施拉德探员  -在  长官
- Agent Schrader. - Sir!
-很高兴有你加入  -谢谢  谢谢
- Glad to have you on board. - Thanks,thanks.
-这些人都好相处吧  -是的  真是帮好兄弟
- Everybody getting you settled in? - Great group of guys.
还有姐妹们 都是好兄弟好姐妹
And gals. Got guys...Guys and gals.
很好  你来得真是太巧了
That's good. You couldn't have picked a better time to arrive.
正准备给贩毒集团一个重创呢
About to put a big dent in the cartel.
-对吗  万科  -是的  长官
- Right, Vanco? - Yes, sir.
[国家原子能博物馆]
兄弟  好好看看
Bro, check it out.
这是你屁股的卫星像片
It's a satellite picture of you farting.
胖子和瘦皮猴
Fat Man and Little Boy.
看来就是你们俩了
Sounds like you two.
我裤裆里的才是胖子  你个混蛋
I got your Fat Man in my pants, bitch.
小心点
Watch it.
那不是真的  笨蛋
It ain't real, dumbass.
叫你小心点就是了
Watch it, is all.
你才小心点
You watch it.
我是海森堡
I'm Heisenberg.
你就是海森堡
You're Heisenberg?
我记得你  你就是那个制毒的
I remember you.You were the cook.
先把这事了结了吧
Let's get this over with.
杰西在哪
Where's Jesse?
在忙
Busy.
他很酷
That's cool.
真的很酷
Real cool.
简直太酷了
Totally cool.
都在这里了  一分不少
It's all there. Every dollar.
万一你想  点一下的话
In case you want to, like, count it.
在这吗
Here?
我只是说说
I'm just saying...
说说而已  我们很合作  老兄
Just saying, like, we cool, yo.
我们知道在替谁办事  忠心耿耿  绝不含糊
We ain't got no confusion and interpretation as to who we work for.
老兄  我敢对上帝发誓  绝无虚言
Man, that's church, yo.For real.
你们听到什么了
What have you heard?
杰西真的
Did Jesse really...
我是说  他真的
I mean, did he really...
用台自动取款机砸了那家伙的脑袋吗
Squash that dude's head with an ATM machine?
这是谁说的
Who's saying that?
老兄  已经都传遍了
Damn, man, it's all over town.
每个人都在说  牛逼
Everybody's like, whoa, snap!
通常我都得追着那些家伙要钱
Usually I got to chase dudes down for their money.
但今天  每个人都乖乖付钱了
But today,Everybody's paying up.
是真的  不骗你
True that.Serious.
但他真的
But, like...
他真这么干了吗
He really did it?
别说是我说出来的
You didn't hear that from me.
午饭吃多了
Big lunch.
-给你这个  -很好  怀特小姐
- Here you go. - Very good, Miss White.
我们会审核您的申请  并尽快通知您
We'll consider your application and let you know.
谢谢
Thank you
我只想提一下  我以前在这工作过
I'd just like to mention that I have worked here before.
真的
Really?
您预产期什么时候
When are you due?
-还有几个月吧  -恭喜你了
- Several months. - Congratulations.
我看到了  会计部
I see.Accounting department.
你是四年前离职的
You left us four years ago?
家庭原因
Family.
我们一定尽早通知你  谢谢你来应聘
We'll definitely let you know.Thank you for coming by.
事实上  我想见见泰德·贝内克可以吗
Actually, may I see Ted Beneke?
我想他还记得我
I think he'll remember me.
很不巧  今天贝内克先生很忙
Mr. Beneke's very busy today,unfortunately.
如果可以的话  我想
If it's okay, I'll just...
女士
Ma'am.
斯凯勒
Skyler
天哪  看看你
Oh, my God, look at you.
你好  泰德
Hey, Ted.
快进来
Come in.
电话别转进来  玛格丽特 谢谢
No calls, Margaret.Thanks.
先坐吧
Sit down right here.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看上去美极了
You look great.
是男孩女孩  还是想最后再揭晓谜底
A boy or a girl,or are you keeping it a secret?
是女孩  我们都很高兴
It's a little girl.We're very excited.
我想也是  儿女双全了
I'll bet.One of each.
小沃尔特怎么样
How's Walt Jr.?
高一了  像野草一样开始疯长
Tenth grade and he's just growing like a weed.
现在已经比我都高了
He's taller than I am now.
我猜他以后至少有6英尺3  6英尺4[1.9-1.93米]
I'm betting 6'3", 6'4" by the time he's finished.
长得挺英俊  感谢上帝
Wow, handsome. Oh, my God.
遗传好啊
Good genes.
说起电影明星  那不会是你家的双胞胎吧
Speaking of movie stars,those can't be the twins.
对  就是她们
Yep, that's them.
-她们真漂亮  -是很漂亮
- They're gorgeous. - Yes, they are.
她们自己也这么认为
And they know it.
-看来我以后有得操心了  是吧  -就是
- I'm in real trouble there, huh? - Yeah.
-这么说  接你父亲班了  -是啊
- So, the big office? - Yeah.
很奇怪  是不
Weird, isn't it?
我还是觉得是我爸在这办公
I still think of it as my dad's.
我很想他
I miss him.
我也是
Me, too.
我很想让他为我感到骄傲
I'd like to think he'd be proud.
去年是我们业绩最好的一年
Last year was our best year yet.
他会为你骄傲的
He'd be proud.
沃尔特  他怎么样
Walt, how's he doing?
他一切都好
He is doing great.
他一直很努力
He's plugging away.
太好了
Great.
-他还在教书吗  -是的
- He still teaching? - Yeah.
-帮我转达下问候  -我一定转达
- You tell him I said hello. - I will definitely do that.
老实说  泰德
To be honest, Ted,
我这次来  不只是来问个好的
I didn't just stop by to say hello.
我是来申请份数据录入工作的
I was applying for the data entry job.
你开什么玩笑
You're kidding.
你可一直是我们最棒的记账员
You were like our go-to book keeper.
经济形势  你也知道的  所以...
The economy, you know, so...
数据录入  那怎么可以
Well, data entry,that'd be a mistake.
做回你的老本行  怎么样
How about...get your old job back?
公司发展得很快
We're expanding and...
咱私下说说啊  整个部门简直就一团乱
Between you and me, that whole department is pretty much of a mess.
这工作你完全可以胜任
Your work would be cut out for you. But...
而且我们需要你帮忙
We could use your help.
好的
Ok
现在这些是我们地盘  对吗  目前来说
Now, this is our territory, right? Currently.
你在听吗
Hello?
-对的  -然后  看看这里
- Correct. - All right, then. Now, look at this.
这里这里这里  还有这里
Here, here, here and here.
这些对你来说意味着什么
What does that look like to you?
机会  赚大钱的机会  就是这个
Opportunities. Golden ones.That's what that looks like.
看看这里  整个城市商机无限啊
Look.It's an entire city full of buyers.
那么  为什么我们还没扩展到那里
Now, why aren't we exploiting that?
-因为那不是我们的地盘  -因为我们缺乏进取心
- Because it's not our territory.- Because we lack initiative.
-进取心  -你得雇用更多的毒贩
- Initiative? - You need to employ more dealers.
增加两倍  三倍的人手
Double, triple your crew.
我见到的那三个人  每人都应该找三个  六个
Those three I met...they should each have three, six,
九个下家  为他们工作
Nine sub-dealers working for them.
指数级的增长  那才是关键
Exponential growth...that's the key.
那不是我们的地盘
It's not our territory.
你听得懂吗  老兄
Man, you follow me, here?
我们要是介入到别人的地盘
We go rolling into these neighborhoods,
那些家伙不会放过我们的
Other crews ain't going to take kindly.
-你明白吗  -当然  他们会不高兴
- You understand? - Sure. They won't like it.
但我敢说他们不会把我们怎么样的
But I say they're not going to do a thing about it.
听着  杰西  不
Listen, Jesse.-No.
杰西
Jesse.
局势已经变了  消息已经传开了
The game has changed.The word is out.
说你是个惹不得的人
And you are a killer.
-你在说什么呢  -显然这点已经人尽皆知了
- What are you talking about?- Apparently it's all over town.
有人惹了你  你大发雷霆
Somebody crossed you. You got angry.
用台自动取款机砸碎了他的脑袋
You crushed their skull with an ATM machine.
-但这根本不是事实  -谁在乎呢
- But that's not how it happened. - Who cares?
只要我们的竞争对手  而不是警察  相信这点
Just as long as it's our competitors who believe it and not the police.
-我的天  -你没看出来这事有多棒吗
- My God.- Don't you see how great this is?
你看  你就是一个...
Look, you are a...
杰西  看着我
Jesse, look at me.
你  就是条河豚
You... are a blowfish.
-什么  -河豚  想想看
- What? - A blowfish. Think about it.
体型不大  动作不快  也不灵活
Small in stature,not swift, not cunning.
很容易成为盘中餐  但是河豚
Easy prey for predators.But the blowfish
有一项秘密武器  对吗
Has a secret weapon, doesn't he?
河豚会怎么做  杰西
What does the blowfish do, Jesse?
河豚会怎么做
What does the blowfish do?
-我不知道  -河豚会膨胀
- I don't know... - The blowfish puffs up.
河豚能自我膨胀到平常的四到五倍大
The blowfish puffs himself up four or five times larger than normal.
为什么  它为什么会这么做呢
And why? Why does he do that?
这样能让它具有威慑力  这就是原因
So that it makes him intimidating,that's why.
威慑力
Intimidating,
这样才能把其他更可怕的鱼都吓跑
So that the other scarier fish are scared off.
而这就你是  你就是那条河豚
And that's you.You are a blowfish.
知道了吗  所有这些都是种错觉
You see? It's just all an illusion.
明白了吗  这就是个烟雾弹
See? It's nothing but air.
现在
Now,
谁还敢跟河豚对着干呀  杰西
Who messes with the blowfish, Jesse?
-没人敢  -你说得真TM对
- Nobody.- You're damn right.
-我是河豚  -你是河豚
- I'm a blowfish.- You are a blowfish.
-再说一遍  -我是河豚
- Say it again.- I'm a blowfish.
-郑重其事地说一遍  -我就是河豚
- Say it like you mean it.- I'm a blowfish!
就是这样
That's it.
河豚要来一下这个
Blowfishing this up.
商品型录  把那本型录给我  好吗
The SkyMall.Give me the SkyMall, would you?
万科  这新来的不会讲西班牙话吗
Vanco, new guy don't speak Spanish?
怎么了
What's up?
白佬
Hey, white boy,
最好学着点西班牙语  懂吗
Better learn espanol, huh?
这里可不是美国的密苏里州布兰森  懂我意思吗
This ain't Branson, Missouri.You know what I'm talking about?
我看这样吧
You know what?
我来教你
I'll teach you.
意思就是
It means
"我们来做个交易吧"
"Let's make a deal."
继续啊  我们等着呢
So go ahead.We're waiting.
快看  快看
Vaya, vaya.
就在这里
Right here.
商品编号SS4G
Item SS4G.
老洋基球场最有一场比赛的纪念棒球
Yankee Stadium, "Final Season"Commemorative Baseball,
有德雷克·杰特亲笔签名 [洋基队队长]
Hand-signed by Derek Jeter.
万科  快把这记下来
Vanco, write this down.
老兄  快看这个
Man, watch out.
661OOZBG号
661OOZBG.
大号地垫
Large size floor runner.
看看这个
Look at that.
铺在地上的一块小地毯
It's a rug you put on the floor,
只不过看起来跟百元美钞一样
Except for it looks like a hundred dollar bill.
我爱死它了  给我来20个
I love them.Get me 20 of them.
我要把家里铺满这个
I'm going to put them all over my casa.
我们会给你买三个
We'll get you three.
-给我买10个吧  -最多5个
- You give me ten.- Five.
别拿我们开涮了  好吧
How about you stop jerking us off, here?
到底什么时候交易  告诉我们地点和时间
Where's the meet? When's it going down?
看来白佬不喜欢跟我们做生意是吧
White boy don't like "Let's make a deal."
你再这么浪费他的时间  白佬要给你好看了
White boy's going to kick your ass,you don't stop wasting his time.
施拉德
Schrader...
白佬
White boy.
我的名字叫玳瑁
My name's Tortuga.
你知道什么意思嘛
You know what that means?
要我猜的话  西班牙语里应该是"傻帽"的意思
Well, if I had to guess,I'd say that's Spanish for "asshole".
"玳瑁"意思就是"乌龟"
"Tortuga" means "turtle."
我就是这样的
That's me.
做事不慌不忙
I take my time,
但最后的赢家总是我
But I always win.
这倒提醒我了  快看这个  我以前见过的
That reminds me.Wait, I seen this earlier, look it.
这个太棒了  伙计
This is awesome, homes.
就在这里  看看这个
Right there.Look at that.
安然的乌龟花园的雕塑
The Tranquil Tortoise garden sculpture.
这个一定要来两个
Definitely two of those.
快来看看  快看
Check it out.Mira.
真的很像啊
Good likeness.
汉克在那干得不错  前景一片光明
Hank's doing great down there.He's really making inroads.
当然了  他可是个英雄
I'm sure he is.He's a hero, after all.
-那你会去挨尔帕索吗[德州西南部]  -拜托
- So, you going to go down to El Paso?  - Please.
我们这儿就够落后的了
It's third-world enough around here.
再说他也忙得根本没时间
They keep him busy every second.
他们马上就有个大行动
He's already got some big operation going, some kind
好像是啥秘密行动吧  他什么都不说
Of hush-hush deal. He couldn't tell me a thing about it except
-就说是个境外行动  -听起来热血沸腾啊
- It's on the other side of the border.- That sounds exciting.
他在那很安全的  对吗
He's being safe, right?
他老说一直就做些办公室工作
He says he's mostly riding a desk
咱私下说说啊  我还巴不得这样呢
Which between you and me, is how I want it.
说到办公室工作
Speaking of riding desks...
今天我找了份工作
I got myself a job today.
你不是吧
You did not.
挺着这么个大肚子
As big as you are?
多谢关心
Thank you.
我只是想说
You know I just mean...
在哪儿  跟谁呀
Where? With who?
合着还有人愿意跟个大肚子共事啊
Well, someone willing to work around that, apparently.
-是贝内克的公司  -你不是吧
- Beneke. - You did not.
对你毛手毛脚的那位还在那吗
Is Mr. Grabby-Hands still there?
玛丽  只有圣诞晚会上那一次嘛
Marie.It was one time at a Christmas party,
而且他当时已经醉到话都讲不清了
And he was so drunk he was practically slurring his words.
是你自己在给他找借口吧
Just what you want in an executive.
而且他也反复道过歉了
And he apologized profusely.
再说他是有家室的人了
Plus, he's married, has a family.
肯定也不愿被冠个性骚扰的罪名吧
He doesn't want to get sued for sexual harassment.
这种事  绝不会再发生了
It will not...happen again.
你们手头真那么紧吗
Is money that tight?
是的
Yeah.
我们很乐意帮你们的
You know we can always help out.
不用了玛丽  你知道沃尔特这个人的  他
No,Marie.You know Walt.He would just...
说曹操曹操到
Speak of the devil.
你们怎么样  在聊什么
How are you? What's up?
-没聊什么  你怎么样  -很好
- Nothing much. How's things with you? - Good.
-晚餐一小时后就好了  -谢谢  亲爱的
- Dinner will be about an hour. And...- Thanks, honey.
-没啥事吧  -一切都好
- Everything okay?- Everything's perfect.
这个是葡萄干小麦片
This is Raisin Bran,
-不是葡萄干麦脆  -那又如何  一样的嘛
- Not Raisin Bran Crunch. - So? Same thing.
不一样的
Not the same thing.
那这样吧  下次你去超市买东西
I'll tell you what.Why don't you do the grocery shopping?
这样你就可以想买啥就买啥了  这想法好
And then you can get whatever you want. Great!
妈  这没那么复杂的
It's not that hard, Mom.
-盒子上有写"脆"字的就好  -别纠结了
- It says "crunch" on the box.- You're pushing it.
早上好
Morning.
嗨 老爸  - 嗨
Hi,dad.-Hi.
老爸  注意到什么了吗
Dad, notice anything?
今天要去参加葬礼吗
Is there a funeral today?
葬礼  天哪  我看起来有那么糟吗
A funeral? Christ, do I look that bad?
不是  不是...
No,no no..
妈妈找了份工作
Mom got a job.
工作  为什么
A job? Why?
要我拿支票本给你看看吗-不用
Do I need to get out the checkbook and show you?-No.
以你现在的情况  这么做好吗-没事 没事
Is this a good idea in your condition?-No no.
医生说我可以一直工作到临产
The doctor said I can work practically up until I go into labor.
而且就是文职  我只要一直坐着就行了
And it's just an office job. I'm just sitting on my butt.
在哪上班
Where?
贝内克的公司
Beneke.
我又回会计部工作了
I'm back working in the accounting department.
斯凯勒
Skyler
那焊接烟尘之类的怎么办
What about the welding fumes?
你当初不就是为这离职的吗
Isn't that why you had to quit in the first place?
他们之后就开始注重环保了
They've gone green since then.
现在都用类似绿色焊接技术啥的了
They have some kind of green welding or something.
我过去的时候  没闻到什么味
I didn't smell anything when I was in there.
贝内克先生不是过世了吗 是啊
Didn't Mr. Beneke pass away?Yeah.
-现在那边谁管事  -泰德
- Who's running things? - Ted.
儿子接班了
The son.
好了  我得走了
Anyway, I have got to go.
我可不想回去工作的第一天就迟到
I don't want to be late my first day back.
再见-再见
Bye-Bye
-祝我好运  -好运
- Wish me luck. - Good luck.
再见
Bye
你总算出洞了
You left your cave.
我有点想我的电视了
I was kind of missing my TV.
正想着去好市多[大型超市]  买个贼大的宽屏回来
I was thinking maybe I'd hit Costco.Snag a big-ass wide screen.
那么
So...
你在画什么
What you drawing?
靠
Damn.
画得真棒
That's good.
让我很想照着纹上一个
It'd make a hell of a tat.
-就是做这个用的  -真的吗
- That's the plan.- Really?
我在阿尔布开克的一家纹身店里兼职
I work part-time down at ABQ Ink.
靠谱
Right on.
你真是个好画家
You're a real good drawer.
我以前也画过一点
I used to do a little of that.
你以前也画过画
You used to be a drawer, too?
那怎么不画了
What stopped you?
你知道的  就是
You know, just...
来  跟我说说
So, tell me something.
你这算个什么纹身艺术家啊
What kind of tattoo artist has...
自己都没纹身的
No tattoos?
这话题转得够快的啊
That's way too big a commitment.
嘿！哥们.你是平克曼
Hey.man.You're Pinkman.
真有种  大家都在议论你呢
You're the man! Everybody's been talking about you.
老兄  真有你的  继续保持
Right on, man.Keep it real.
-平克曼是吧  -是
- Pinkman  - Yeah.
我以为你叫杰克逊
I thought your name was Jackson.
你那线人叫"乌龟"还真没叫错
Your snitch has really earned his nickname.
我们这是要等到明天吗
Are we just on manana time?
他们会来的
They'll show.
为什么这么说
Why's that?
又给了更多的商品目录让他挑吗
You got more catalogs for him to clean out?
是醒目形象[邮购商]还是陶仓[家居品牌]
You know, Sharper Image or Pottery Barn?
他们到底怎么想的
派这么个言语不通的大嘴巴过来
政治手段  老兄  政治
还说是什么了不起的大英雄  我看是扯淡
也许在阿尔布开克是英雄
到这儿就行不通了
有什么我该知道的吗
Something I need to know about?
什么  刚刚吗  不是啦老兄
What? That? No,man.
我们只是在称颂你呢
We were just, singing your praises.
很高兴有你加入
Glad to have you.
欢迎加入我们
Welcome aboard.
那是你们的人吗
Is that your guy?
我想那就是你们的人
I think that's your guy.
他该死的上那干嘛去了
What the hell is he doing down there?
你去哪啊
Where you going?
这儿需要证物袋对吗  很大的证物袋
We need an evidence bag, right? Pretty big one.
怎么回事  施拉德
What's the matter Schrader?
以前从没见过龟背上驮着的人头吗
You act like you never saw a severed human head on a tortoise before.
欢迎来到
Welcome to...
老天爷啊  我的腿
God damn, my leg.
游戏规则变了
The game has changed.
这里是我们的天下了
This is our city.
知道吗  都是我们的了
All right? All of it.
整个城市都是
The whole damn place.
都是我们的地盘
Our territory.
我们要在这当家做主
We're staking our claim.
啥时出货在哪出货  都由我们说了算
We sell when we want, where we want.
我们都要称王称霸  明白吗
We're going to be kings. Understand?
当然  我做国王  你们就是王公贵族什么的
I'm going to be king and you guys will be princes or dukes or something.
-我想做骑士  -先说最重要的
- I want to be a knight. - First thing's first.
我们得发展更多的下家  跑腿的  懂吗
We got to get more dealers.Foot soldiers.Right?
这些人给你们干活
Now they'll be working for you.
你们跟着我干  他们又跟着你们干
You're working for me,and they're working for you.
听懂了吗
You follow me?
一层一层的
Layered,
像玉米脆饼一样  这叫指数生长
Like nachos.Exponential growth.
这才叫成功
Now that's Success,
大大的成功
With a capital "S".
干得好  干得好
Straight up.Straight up.
-一定能成  -真TM酷
- For shizzle. - Frigging awesome.
搞定了
We're set.
兄弟们都准备好了  我们要赚大钱了
Our boys are ready.Gonna be some mad cheddar.
怀特先生  赚大钱啊  大堆大堆的美钞
Cheddar, Mr. White.Fat stacks, dead presidents.
都是现钞
Cash money.
我们要占领整座城市
We're going to own this city.
我们开价不够高
We're not charging enough.
什么
What?
垄断市场  再抬高价格
Corner the market,then raise the price.
简单的经济学原理
Simple economics.
泰德  进来啊
Ted. Come on in.
-看来他们都帮你安排好了  -是的  非常周到
- Looks like they got you all set up.- Yeah. It's perfect.
离洗手间够近  我就不用挺着大肚走太远
I am close enough to the bathroom not to waddle too far,
非常贴心
And that's very nice.
我想那是在讨好你吧-是啊
I figured that might be a deal-breaker.Yeah.
听我说
Listen, I...
我想感谢你让我回来工作
I wanted to thank you for having me back.
你用不着谢我  公司需要你
You don't have to thank me.I need you.
现在喝酒好像有点早  是吧
It's a little early for wine, isn't it?
糟糕  是葡萄汁  我早上给女儿做早餐来着
Damn. It's grape juice. I've been making the girls breakfast in the morning.
那丹尼斯怎么样了
How's Denise doing?
我们一年前就分手了
We split up about a year ago.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
她现在肯定更开心  我也是  大部分时间都是
She's definitely happier now.I guess I am, too, most days.
我们从高中就在一起了
Together since high school.
是啊  我记得
I remember that.
总之
Anyway...
-我也不知道  人是会变的吧  -我猜也是
- I don't know. People change. - I guess
我只想说  欢迎你
Anyway,I just wanted to welcome you...
欢迎回来
welcome you back.
那就自动贩售机那再见咯
I'll see you around the vending machines.
好的
OK.
我们该找一天一起吃饭  像过去一样
We should have lunch one day.Like old times.
当然
Sure.
探测卫星信号
搜索中...
-你好  -好你个头
- Hi. - Hi yourself.
听我说
So, listen.
我其实不叫杰西·杰克逊
My name's not really Jesse Jackson.
我叫杰西·平克曼
It's Jesse Pinkman.
你看到的那个人
And that guy you met,
他也不是我老爸
He's not my dad.
你不会把我赶出去的
You're not going to kick me out,
对吗
Are you?
我还真挺喜欢这里的
'Cause I actually really like it here.
你做的事跟我没关
I don't make it my business what you do.
只要别在这干就行
So long as you don't do it here.
我说  我新买了个超赞的宽屏电视
So, I got this kick-ass new flat-screen.
想看看吗
Want to see?
这玩意能让黑色看起来
It's got that thing where the blacks are, like,
真的真的很黑
you know, really,really, really black,
还有
And the...
杜比6.0环绕之类的
Dolby six-point-whatever,
所以效果肯定超震撼的
So it'll really rock the house.
不过  我会把声音调小点的
But I'll, you know...I'll keep it way down.
当然会的
Of course.
探测卫星信号
搜索中...
真不明白这该死的怎么弄这么久
I don't know what the hell's taking so long.
拜托  快点吧
Come on.